<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<databaseChangeLog
  xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog
                      http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-4.6.xsd">
  <changeSet author="Neven Jakopčić" id="1638034938-1-genres">
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="genre">
      <column name="id" value="1"/>
      <column name="name" value="classics"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="genre">
      <column name="id" value="2"/>
      <column name="name" value="philosophy"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="genre">
      <column name="id" value="3"/>
      <column name="name" value="thriller"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="genre">
      <column name="id" value="4"/>
      <column name="name" value="psychology"/>
    </insert>
  </changeSet>

  <changeSet author="Neven Jakopčić" id="1638034938-2-authors">
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="author">
      <column name="id" value="1"/>
      <column name="name" value="Thomas Hobbes"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="author">
      <column name="id" value="2"/>
      <column name="name" value="St. Augustine"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="author">
      <column name="id" value="3"/>
      <column name="name" value="Bret Easton Ellis"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="author">
      <column name="id" value="4"/>
      <column name="name" value="Jane Austen"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="author">
      <column name="id" value="5"/>
      <column name="name" value="Carl Jung"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="author">
      <column name="id" value="6"/>
      <column name="name" value="Plato"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="author">
      <column name="id" value="7"/>
      <column name="name" value="J. D. Salinger"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="author">
      <column name="id" value="8"/>
      <column name="name" value="F. Scott Fitzgerald"/>
    </insert>
  </changeSet>

  <changeSet author="Neven Jakopčić" id="1638034938-3-books">
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="1"/>
      <column name="title">Leviathan</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="2"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="1"/>
      <column name="description">
        Written during the chaos of the English Civil War, Thomas Hobbes' Leviathan asks how, in a world of violence and horror,
can we stop ourselves from descending into anarchy? Hobbes' case for a 'common-wealth' under a powerful
sovereign - or 'Leviathan' - to enforce security and the rule of law, shocked his contemporaries, and his book was publicly burnt
for sedition the moment it was published. But his penetrating work of political philosophy - now fully revised and with
a new introduction for this edition - opened up questions about the nature of statecraft and society that influenced governments
across the world.
      </column>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="2"/>
      <column name="title">Confessions</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="2"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="2"/>
      <column name="description">
        The Confessions is a spiritual autobiography, covering the first 35 years of Augustine's life,
with particular emphasis on Augustine's spiritual development and how he accepted Christianity. The Confessions is divided into 13 books.
Books 1 through 9 contain Augustine's life story. Book 10 is an exploration of memory. Books 11 through 13 are detailed interpretations
of the first chapter of Genesis, which describes the creation of the world.
      </column>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="3"/>
      <column name="title">American Psycho</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="3"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="3"/>
      <column name="description">
        Patrick Bateman is twenty-six and he works on Wall Street, he is handsome, sophisticated, charming and intelligent.
He is also a psychopath. Taking us to head-on collision with America's greatest dream—and its worst nightmare—American Psycho is bleak,
bitter, black comedy about a world we all recognise but do not wish to confront.
      </column>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="4"/>
      <column name="title">Pride and Prejudice</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="1"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="4"/>
      <column name="description">
        Since its immediate success in 1813, Pride and Prejudice has remained one of the most popular novels in the English language.
Jane Austen called this brilliant work "her own darling child" and its vivacious heroine, Elizabeth Bennet,
"as delightful a creature as ever appeared in print." The romantic clash between the opinionated Elizabeth and her proud beau, Mr. Darcy,
is a splendid performance of civilized sparring. And Jane Austen's radiant wit sparkles as her characters dance a delicate quadrille of
flirtation and intrigue, making this book the most superb comedy of manners of Regency England.
      </column>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="5"/>
      <column name="title">Man and His Symbols</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="4"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="5"/>
      <column name="description">
        Man and His Symbols owes its existence to one of Jung's own dreams. The great psychologist dreamed that his work was understood by
a wide public, rather than just by psychiatrists, and therefore he agreed to write and edit this fascinating book. Here, Jung examines the
full world of the unconscious, whose language he believed to be the symbols constantly revealed in dreams. Convinced that dreams offer
practical advice, sent from the unconscious to the conscious self, Jung felt that self-understanding would lead to a full
and productive life. Thus, the reader will gain new insights into himself from this thoughtful volume, which also illustrates
symbols throughout history. Completed just before his death by Jung and his associates, it is clearly addressed to the general reader.
      </column>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="6"/>
      <column name="title">Modern Man in Search of a Soul</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="4"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="5"/>
      <column name="description">
        Considered by many to be one of the most important books in the field of psychology, Modern Man in Search of a Soul is a
comprehensive introduction to the thought of Carl Gustav Jung. In this book, Jung examines some of the most contested and crucial areas
in the field of analytical psychology, including dream analysis, the primitive unconscious, and the relationship between psychology
and religion. Additionally, Jung looks at the differences between his theories and those of Sigmund Freud, providing a valuable basis
for anyone interested in the fundamentals of psychoanalysis.
      </column>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="7"/>
      <column name="title">The Republic</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="2"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="6"/>
      <column name="description">
        Presented in the form of a dialogue between Socrates and three different interlocutors, this classic text is an enquiry into
the notion of a perfect community and the ideal individual within it. During the conversation, other questions are raised:
what is goodness?; what is reality?; and what is knowledge? The Republic also addresses the purpose of education and the role of both
women and men as guardians of the people. With remarkable lucidity and deft use of allegory, Plato arrives at a depiction of
a state bound by harmony and ruled by philosopher kings.
      </column>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="8"/>
      <column name="title">Catcher in the Rye</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="1"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="7"/>
      <column name="description">
        The hero-narrator of The Catcher in the Rye is an ancient child of sixteen, a native New Yorker named Holden Caulfield.
Through circumstances that tend to preclude adult, secondhand description, he leaves his prep school in Pennsylvania and goes
underground in New York City for three days. The boy himself is at once too simple and too complex for us to make any final comment
about him or his story. Perhaps the safest thing we can say about Holden is that he was born in the world not just strongly attracted to
beauty but, almost, hopelessly impaled on it. There are many voices in this novel: children's voices, adult voices,
underground voices-but Holden's voice is the most eloquent of all. Transcending his own vernacular, yet remaining marvelously
faithful to it, he issues a perfectly articulated cry of mixed pain and pleasure. However, like most lovers and clowns and poets of the
higher orders, he keeps most of the pain to, and for, himself. The pleasure he gives away, or sets aside, with all his heart.
It is there for the reader who can handle it to keep.
      </column>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book">
      <column name="id" value="9"/>
      <column name="title">The Great Gatsby</column>
      <column name="genre_id" value="1"/>
      <column name="author_id" value="8"/>
      <column name="description">
        The Great Gatsby, F. Scott Fitzgerald's third book, stands as the supreme achievement of his career.
This exemplary novel of the Jazz Age has been acclaimed by generations of readers. The story is of the fabulously wealthy Jay Gatsby
and his new love for the beautiful Daisy Buchanan, of lavish parties on Long Island at a time when The New York Times noted
"gin was the national drink and sex the national obsession," it is an exquisitely crafted tale of America in the 1920s.
The Great Gatsby is one of the great classics of twentieth-century literature.
      </column>
    </insert>
  </changeSet>

  <changeSet author="Neven Jakopčić" id="1638034938-4-book-reservations">
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book_reservation">
      <column name="id" value="1"/>
      <column name="book_id" value="1"/>
      <column name="borrower_id" value="2"/>
      <column name="borrowed_date" value="2021-11-25"/>
      <column name="due_date" value="2021-12-09"/>
      <column name="returned" value="true"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book_reservation">
      <column name="id" value="2"/>
      <column name="book_id" value="1"/>
      <column name="borrower_id" value="3"/>
      <column name="borrowed_date" value="2021-11-27"/>
      <column name="due_date" value="2021-12-11"/>
      <column name="returned" value="false"/>
    </insert>
    <insert schemaName="public" tableName="book_reservation">
      <column name="id" value="3"/>
      <column name="book_id" value="2"/>
      <column name="borrower_id" value="2"/>
      <column name="borrowed_date" value="2021-11-25"/>
      <column name="due_date" value="2021-12-09"/>
      <column name="returned" value="true"/>
    </insert>
  </changeSet>
</databaseChangeLog>